Guide to the Bidwell Family Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Correspondence and Personal Papers of Other Bidwell and Related Families, 1750-1952; 1850-1915; Series III
  "Bidwell Family, Individual Members" is arranged alphabetically by the name of the individual family member. There are approximately forty individuals included. See: Appendix I. Correspondence is filed under the name of the family member to whom the letter is written, then alphabetically by the correspondent's last name. Under a given family member's name is his or her correspondence, followed by writings, notebooks and diaries, legal papers and clippings, and photographs, in that order. Except for the correspondence, each of these sections is in chronological order. It is to be noted that not all family members will have material in each of these categories.
  "Correspondence, Writings, and Photographs of Others" is arranged alphabetically.
  - Bidwell Family, General
    - Genealogy and History
      - Bidwells in England; Bidwells in America to the eighth generation, with historical notes (1) (Box 5, Folder 211, Reel 3U)
      - Bidwells in early Connecticut (circa 7) (Box 5, Folder 212, Reel 3U)
      - Records of Bidwell births, deaths, and marriages (3), 1716-1840 (Box 5, Folder 213, Reel 3U)
      - Record of the descendants of Adonijah Bidwell (1716-1784) to the 5th generation. Includes partial records of Partridge, Welsh, Williams, Willcox, and Dench families (1), 1716-1883 (Box 5, Folder 214, Reel 3U)
      - Bidwell family record books (2), 1716-1908 (Box 5, Folder 215, Reel 3U)
      - Bidwell houses, Monterey, Massachusetts and Willmanville, Kansas (3), 1750, 1793, undated (Box 5, Folder 216, Reel 3U)
      - Notes taken from Massachusetts Soldiers and Sailors of the Revolutionary War, vol. II and vol. IV (4) (Box 5, Folder 217, Reel 3U)
      - "Genealogical table showing the connection between the Williams, Gray, Partridge, Hunt, Sergeant, Dwight, Hopkins and Bidwell families" (1), 1838 (Box 5, Folder 218, Reel 3U)
      - Letter of Josiah Brewer to M. S. Bidwell re: Bidwell and Devotion families (1), 1868 (Box 5, Folder 219, Reel 3U)
      - "Bidwell and Allied Families," American Ancestry, vol. IX (1), 1894 (Box 5, Folder 220, Reel 3U)
      - Bidwell Family History, collection of articles re: notable Bidwells and Bidwell family reunions (1), (1912-1941) (Box 5, Folder 221, Reel 3U)
      - Some Bidwell Occupations, Frederick David Bidwell (3), 1915 (Box 5, Folder 222, Reel 3U)
      - Pamphlets of the Bidwell Family Association (4), 1915, undated (Box 5, Folder 223, Reel 3U)
      - Clippings: Bidwell family reunions (4), 1915, 1940, undated (Box 5, Folder 224, Reel 3U)
      - Bidwells in the World War, Frederick David Bidwell (1), 1920 (Box 5, Folder 225, Reel 3U)
      - The Association News (24), 1932 February-1936 August (Box 5, Folder 226, Reel 3U)
      - Correspondence from Frederick D. Bidwell to Alice L. Bidwell re: Bidwell Family Assn. and the General Bidwell Memorial (circa 4) (Box 5, Folder 227, Reel 3U)
      - General Bidwell Memorial (1), Undated (Box 5, Folder 228, Reel 3U)
      - "Ancestry of Gilbert Dench," chart with notes (1) (Box 5, Folder 229, Reel 3U)
      - Devotion history and genealogy (3) (Box 5, Folder 230, Reel 3U)
      - Edward Devotion House Association (1) (Box 5, Folder 231, Reel 3U)
      - "Ancestry of Anne Gibbs," notes on the Gibbs family by John D. Bidwell (2) (Box 5, Folder 232, Reel 3U)
      - Hart family record (5) (Box 5, Folder 233, Reel 3U)
      - Draft of letter to C. F. Jackson from an Orton family member re: disposition of family antiques (1) (Box 5, Folder 234, Reel 3U)
      - Correspondence of John Jackson Orton and Dr. James H. Jackson re: Jackson-Orton family history (3), 1891-1894 (Box 5, Folder 235, Reel 3U)
      - Letter of John Jackson Orton to a cousin re: family history (incomplete) (1), 1905 (Box 5, Folder 236, Reel 3U)
      - Letter of Alice W. Knox to Marshall Spring Bidwell re: Knox-Jenks family record (1), 1867 (Box 5, Folder 237, Reel 3U)
      - The Orton Genealogy, by Edward Orton (1), 1896 (Box 5, Folder 238, Reel 3U)
      - A Supplement to the Orton Genealogy (1), 1900 (Box 5, Folder 239, Reel 3U)
      - Partial list of descendants of Thomas Orton, Windsor, Connecticut (2) (Box 5, Folder 240, Reel 3U)
      - Partridge family record, includes marriages to Joseph Smith and Brigham Young (1) (Box 6, Folder 241, Reel 4U)
      - Spring-Gray family genealogies, also includes relationship to Williams, Cutting, Marshall, and Convers families (4) (Box 6, Folder 242, Reel 4U)
      - Life History of Marshall Spring, M.D. (1741-1818) (2) (Box 6, Folder 243, Reel 4U)
      - Letters of Henry W. Taylor to Marshall Spring Bidwell re: Taylor genealogy (included chart) (4) (Box 6, Folder 244, Reel 4U)
      - Letter of Reverend James T. Dickinson to Marshall S. Bidwell re: Taylor family genealogy (1), 1869 (Box 6, Folder 245, Reel 4U)
      - Genealogical charts of the Taylor family (2) (Box 6, Folder 246, Reel 4U)
      - Warren genealogy and history (circa 5) (Box 6, Folder 247, Reel 4U)
      - John Welsh of Norwich, Welsh coat of arms described (2) (Box 6, Folder 248, Reel 4U)
      - Maternal ancestry of Luna S. Welsh (1) (Box 6, Folder 249, Reel 4U)
      - "The Doctors Welsh of Norfolk," The New England Journal of Medicine (2), 1834 May 24 (Box 6, Folder 250, Reel 4U)
      - Benjamin W. Pettibone to Alice L. Bidwell re: Welsh family genealogy (circa 4), 1899 (Box 6, Folder 251, Reel 4U)
      - "The Great Welsh Family of Doctors," The Lure of the Litchfield Hills (1), Undated (Box 6, Folder 252, Reel 4U)
      - Willcox family history (2) (Box 6, Folder 253, Reel 4U)
      - Mabel Harlakenden, pedigree of [empty] (Box 6, Folder 254, Reel 4U)
        - Oversize (Box 19, Reel 4U)
      - John Haynes, governor of Connecticut (3) (Box 6, Folder 255, Reel 4U)
      - Men of Massachusetts and Connecticut, genealogical and historical notes (2) (Box 6, Folder 256, Reel 4U)
      - "Young's house in Mount Pleasant," notation by M. S. Bidwell (1) (Box 6, Folder 257, Reel 4U)
    - (Tyringham) Monterey, Massachusetts
      - Parish record of the town of Tyringham, Massachusetts [empty], 1750-1783 (Box 6, Folder 258, Reel 4U)
        See: box 8, folder 292
      - History of the Congregational Society in Monterey, Massachusetts (1), 1750-1900 (Box 6, Folder 259, Reel 4U)
      - "Old Burial-ground, Tyringham" (1), 1789 (Box 6, Folder 260, Reel 4U)
      - Tyringham record book; deaths, historical and legal notes (1), 1807-1866 (Box 6, Folder 261, Reel 4U)
      - "Historical Sketch of the Congregational Church of Monterey, with Report" (1), 1891 (Box 6, Folder 262, Reel 4U)
      - Clippings: "The Original Settlers of our Mountain District," (Bidwells, Jacksons and Ortons included) (2), Undated (Box 6, Folder 263, Reel 4U)
      - Map of Monterey (1), Undated (Box 6, Folder 264, Reel 4U)
      - Clipping: "Cemetery of the Cross-eyed Angels," Tyringham, Massachusetts (description of tombstones of Rev. Adonijah Bidwell and family included) (1), Undated (Box 6, Folder 265, Reel 4U)
      - Photograph of tombstone of Adonijah Bidwell, "Cemetery of the Cross-eyed Angels" (1) (Box 6, Folder 266, Reel 4U)
      - Photographs of Monterey, Massachusetts (4), undated (Box 6, Folder 267, Reel 4U)
    - Writings
      - "The Echo," produced by members of the Bidwell family, New Haven, 1881 March 17 (Box 6, Folder 268, Reel 4U)
      - "The Independent," vol. I, Nos. 1-8; vol. II, No. 9, produced by members of the Bidwell and Barnes families of New Haven, 1877 (Box 6, Folder 269, Reel 4U)
      - "Lake Farm Gobbler," produced by Bidwell children, 1885 August 22 (Box 6, Folder 270, Reel 4U)
      - Recipe book (Box 6, Folder 271, Reel 4U)
    - Memorabilia
      - The First Church in Hartford, history covenent, catalogue of surviving members, 1835 August (Box 6, Folder 272, Reel 4U)
      - List of family antiques by Clara Bidwell Warren (Box 6, Folder 273, Reel 4U)
      - Map of Stockbridge, Massachusetts, indicating family residences, Undated (Box 6, Folder 274, Reel 4U)
      - Mementos and drawings, miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 275, Reel 4U)
      - Songs and verses, miscellaneous (Box 6, Folder 276, Reel 4U)
      - Tombstone inscriptions and epitaphs (Box 6, Folder 277, Reel 4U)
        - Oversize material, Undated (Box 19, Reel 4U)
    - Newspaper Clippings
      - Bidwell family members (Box 7, Folder 278, Reel 4U)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 279, Reel 4U)
      - Families related to Bidwells by marriage
        - Denton, Hallett, Kellog, Hall (Box 7, Folder 280, Reel 4U)
        - (Welsh)-Guiteau-Pettibone (Box 7, Folder 281, Reel 4U)
        - Orton (Box 7, Folder 282, Reel 4U)
        - Partridge (includes Partridge photo) (Box 7, Folder 283, Reel 4U)
        - Warren (Box 7, Folder 284, Reel 4U)
        - Welsh, 1880-1934 (Box 7, Folder 285, Reel 4U)
    - Photographs
      - Album: Bidwell family (including Cone, Karrick, Kellogg) (Box 7, Folder 286, Reel 4U)
      - Album: Bidwell, Brewer (Box 7, Folder 287, Reel 4U)
      - Album: Bidwell, Brewer and Field families (Box 7, Folder 288, Reel 4U)
      - Bidwell family photos, unidentified and miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 289, Reel 4U)
      - Cone family photos, miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 289a, Reel 4U)
      - Warren family photos, miscellaneous (Box 7, Folder 290, Reel 4U)
      - Photos of Sagamore Beach, Massachusetts, Circa 1907 (Box 7, Folder 291, Reel 4U)
  - Bidwell Family, Individual Members
    - Rev. Adonijah Bidwell (1716-1784)
      - Parish record, Tyringham, Massachusetts (1), 1750-1783 (Box 8, Folder 292, Reel 4U)
      - Sermons (4), 1751-1777 (Box 8, Folder 293, Reel 4U)
      - Epitaphs for the tombstones of Adonijah and Jemima Bidwell, written by Barnabas Bidwell (2) (Box 8, Folder 294, Reel 4U)
      - Photo of tombstone of Rev. Adonijah Bidwell, with epitaph (Box 8, Folder 295, Reel 4U)
      - Clipping: Adonijah Bidwell's clock (Box 8, Folder 296, Reel 4U)
    - Adonijah Bidwell (1794-1830)
      - Teacher's report on the good conduct of Adonijah Bidwell, grandson of Rev. Adonijah Bidwell (1) (Box 8, Folder 297, Reel 4U)
    - Alice Cecilia Bidwell (1834-1912)
      - Abbot, Jacob (3), 1868-1877 (Box 8, Folder 298, Reel 4U)
      - Ayres, W. W. re: death of M. S. Bidwell, Jr., 1877 (Box 8, Folder 299, Reel 4U)
      - Beecher, Julia J. (2), 1903-1904 (Box 8, Folder 300, Reel 4U)
      - Bidwell, E. C. [Edwin Curtis?] (2), 1905 (Box 8, Folder 301, Reel 4U)
      - Bidwell, Marshall Spring, Jr. (circa 15), 1854-1857 (Box 8, Folder 302, Reel 4U)
      - Bidwell, Marshall Spring, Jr. (8), 1858 (Box 8, Folder 303, Reel 5U)
      - Bidwell, Marshall S., Jr. (14), 1860-1861 (Box 8, Folder 304, Reel 5U)
      - Bidwell, Marshall S., Jr. (circa 28), 1862 (Box 8, Folder 305, Reel 5U)
      - Bidwell, Marshall S., Jr. (circa 50), 1863 (Box 8, Folder 306, Reel 5U)
      - Bidwell, Marshall S., Jr. (circa 31), 1864 (Box 8, Folder 307, Reel 5U)
      - Bidwell, Marshall S., Jr. (circa 34), 1865 (Box 8, Folder 308, Reel 5U)
      - Bidwell, Marshall S., Jr. (circa 36), 1875, 1876 (Box 8, Folder 309, Reel 5U)
      - Brewer, Justice David J. re: Brewer genealogy (1), 1891 (Box 8, Folder 310, Reel 5U)
      - Cone, Mary Gray Bidwell (1), 1906 (Box 8, Folder 311, Reel 5U)
      - Fitch, John, Jr., re: death of M. S. Bidwell, Jr. [empty], 1877 December (Box 8, Folder 312, Reel 5U)
      - Kip, Helen C. (1), 1901 (Box 8, Folder 313, Reel 5U)
      - Orton, John J. (8), 1910-1911 (Box 8, Folder 314, Reel 5U)
      - Pettibone, A. G. (2), 1898 (Box 8, Folder 315, Reel 5U)
      - Pettibone, Benjamin W. (2), 1899, 1903, 1905 (Box 8, Folder 316, Reel 5U)
      - Warren, Charles Herbert (1), 1906 (Box 8, Folder 317, Reel 5U)
      - Warren, Clara L. Bidwell (ca.23), 1888-1898, 1906 (Box 8, Folder 318, Reel 5U)
      - Obituary notices (1), 1912 (Box 8, Folder 319, Reel 5U)
    - Alice J. (Hart) Bidwell (1840-1929)
      - Bidwell, Marshall S., Jr. (2) (Box 9, Folder 320, Reel 5U)
      - D. A. R. membership certificate [empty] (Box 9, Folder 321, Reel 5U)
        - Oversize, 1900 (Box 19, Reel 5U)
      - Settlement of the estate of Alice J. Bidwell (4), 1929, 1939 (Box 9, Folder 322, Reel 5U)
      - Last will and testament of Julia L. Hart, giving Alice J. Bidwell, her daughter, two spoons and naming J. W. Bidwell as executor [copy], 1886 (Box 9, Folder 323, Reel 5U)
      - Last will and testament of Mary L. Hart, naming Alice J. Bidwell, her sister, as a beneficiary [copy], Undated (Box 9, Folder 324, Reel 5U)
    - Alice Louise Bidwell (1872-1919)
      - Bidwell, Frederick D. re: Bidwell Family Association [empty], 1932-1940 (Box 9, Folder 325, Reel 5U)
        See: box 5, folder 227
      - Pettibone, Benjamin W. re: Welsh genealogy and history [empty], 1899 (Box 9, Folder 326, Reel 5U)
        See: box 6, folder 251
      - Diplomas: West Winsted Public School, Young Ladies Institute [empty] (Box 9, Folder 327, Reel 5U)
        - Oversize, 1889, 1891 (Box 19, Reel 5U)
      - D. A. R. certificate of membership [empty] (Box 9, Folder 328, Reel 5U)
        - Oversize, 1900 (Box 19, Reel 5U)
      - Ancestry of Alice L. Bidwell, Winsted, Connecticut (Box 19, Folder 329, Reel 5U)
    - Charles Augustus Bidwell (1842-1933)
      - Bidwell, Lawson Bennett (1), 1879 (Box 9, Folder 330, Reel 5U)
    - Clara Emily Bidwell (1840-1912)
      - Bidwell, Alice C. (2) (Box 9, Folder 331, Reel 5U)
      - Bidwell, Clara Willcox, 1849 (Box 9, Folder 331, Reel 5U)
      - Bidwell, Marshall Spring, Jr. (5), 1860-1862 (Box 9, Folder 332, Reel 5U)
      - Cone, Mary G. Bidwell (2), 1902, 1904 (Box 9, Folder 333, Reel 5U)
      - Fragment of a letter from Clara Emily Bidwell to Mr. Hancy (1), 1904 (Box 9, Folder 334, Reel 5U)
      - Warren, Janet (1), Undated (Box 9, Folder 335, Reel 5U)
      - Willcox, Hassard W. (1), 1902 (Box 9, Folder 336, Reel 5U)
      - Correspondence re: Bidwell collection of shells (circa 15), 1902-1903 (Box 9, Folder 337, Reel 5U)
      - Notebook, 1864, 1867-1875, 1887 (Box 9, Folder 338-339, Reel 6U)
      - Notebook: account of a European trip, 1878 November 6-1880 June 7 (Box 9, Folder 340-341, Reel 6U)
      - Notebook: favorite poems and hymns, Undated (Box 9, Folder 342, Reel 6U)
      - Color drawings by Clara E. Bidwell [and others?], Undated (Box 9, Folder 343, Reel 6U)
      - Passport issued by U. S. Legation in London, 1878 (Box 9, Folder 344, Reel 6U)
      - Souvenirs, N. Y. C. and Germany, Circa 1880 (Box 9, Folder 345, Reel 6U)
      - Last will and testament of Clara E. Bidwell (copy), 1904 (Box 10, Folder 346, Reel 6U)
      - Clippings re: Clara E. Bidwell, 1912, undated (Box 10, Folder 347, Reel 6U)
      - Account of proceedings of Edward J. Hancy as executor of C. E. B.'s will, 1913 (Box 10, Folder 348, Reel 6U)
    - Clara Luna Bidwell
      - Correspondence [empty] (Box 10, Folder 349, Reel 6U)
        See: box 11, folder 360
    - Clara Willcox Bidwell (1798-1862)
      - Bidwell, Marshall Spring, Jr. (3), 1856 (Box 10, Folder 350, Reel 6U)
      - Whitney, Mercy Partridge [missionary to Hawaii] (1), 1828 (Box 10, Folder 351, Reel 6U)
      - Permission of the Canadian government to travel to St. Croix, 1837 (Box 10, Folder 352, Reel 6U)
      - Passport to the West Indies, 1838 December 11 (Box 10, Folder 353, Reel 6U)
      - "In Memoriam: Mrs. Marshall S. Bidwell", 1862 (Box 10, Folder 354, Reel 6U)
    - Edwin Curtis Bidwell (1821-1905)
      - Lecture: "The Birth of a New Science" re: Louis Pasteur, 1902 (Box 10, Folder 355, Reel 6U)
      - Clippings, 1903, undated (Box 10, Folder 356, Reel 6U)
    - Emmeline M. (Bennett) Bidwell (1798-1878)
      - Bidwell, Lawson Bennett (5), 1868-1877 (Box 10, Folder 357, Reel 6U)
      - Bidwell, Lawson Bennett and Henrietta, 1870 (Box 10, Folder 358, Reel 6U)
      - Family wills, 1850, 1878 (Box 10, Folder 358a, Reel 6U)
      - Photos of Emmeline M. Bidwell (Box 10, Folder 359, Reel 6U)
    - Gertrude (Mrs. Charles A.) Bidwell
      - Warren, Clara L. Bidwell (1), 1942 May 10 (Box 11, Folder 360, Reel 6U)
      - Correspondence re: life of Barnabas Bidwell [empty] (Box 11, Folder 361, Reel 6U)
        See: box 1, folder 37
      - Bidwell, Marshall S., Jr. and Alice C. (6), 1866 (Box 11, Folder 362, Reel 6U)
      - Bidwell, Marshall S., Jr. and Alice C. (4), 1865-1866 (Box 11, Folder 363-364, Reel 6U)
    - Henrietta Whitney Brewer Bidwell (1831-1901)
      - Brewer, (Justice) David J. (1), 1858 (Box 11, Folder 364, Reel 6U)
      - Bidwell, Walter D. (2), 1893 (Box 11, Folder 365, Reel 6U)
      - Note from her pupils when governess of Carter family (1), Undated (Box 11, Folder 366, Reel 6U)
      - Clipping: biographical sketch and photo, 1931 May 15 (Box 11, Folder 367, Reel 6U)
      - Portraits of Henrietta Whitney Brewer Bidwell (Box 11, Folder 368, Reel 6U)
    - Jacob Abbott Bidwell (1867-1882)
      - Abbott, Jacob (4), 1869-1873 (Box 11, Folder 369, Reel 6U)
      - Bidwell, Alice C. (2) (Box 11, Folder 370, Reel 6U)
      - Bidwell, Marshall S., Jr. (3) (Box 11, Folder 371, Reel 6U)
      - Bidwell, O. C. (1), 1881 (Box 11, Folder 372, Reel 6U)
      - "Abbott's Paper", 1875 (Box 11, Folder 373, Reel 6U)
      - Obituary notices, 1882 (Box 11, Folder 374, Reel 6U)
    - Jane Raymond Bidwell (1861-1952)
      - Bidwell, Lawson Brewer (2), 1883, 1890 (Box 11, Folder 375, Reel 6U)
      - Brewer, Adele (1), 1930 (Box 11, Folder 376, Reel 6U)
      - Fleming, Robert V. (1), 1948 (Box 11, Folder 377, Reel 6U)
      - Poem by Isaac Metcalf for Jane R. Bidwell's 80th birthday, 1941 (Box 11, Folder 378, Reel 6U)
      - "Memoir of Mrs. Lawson Brewer Bidwell," New England Historical and Genealogical Register, 1952 July (Box 11, Folder 379, Reel 6U)
      - Two portraits of Jane Raymond Bidwell (Box 11, Folder 380, Reel 6U)
    - John Devotion Bidwell (1792-1867)
      - "John D. Bidwell's Book," a record of the events of the War of 1812 (Box 11, Folder 381, Reel 6U)
      - Licenses as justice of the peace in Massachusetts, 1836 January 5, 1856 November 17 (Box 11, Folder 382, Reel 6U)
      - Consecration, 1859 (Box 11, Folder 383, Reel 6U)
      - Receipt of a donation for the Washington Monument, Undated (Box 11, Folder 384, Reel 6U)
    - John Welsh Bidwell, M.D. (1824-1897)
      - Letter to John Bidwell re: California gold fever, 1849 [Jan?] (Box 19, Reel 6U)
      - Diary of a journey from New York to California, 1849 (Box 11, Folder 385, Reel 6U)
      - Berkshire and Pacific Mining Co., co-partnership and contract, 1849 (Box 11, Folder 386, Reel 6U)
      - Clippings re: the life and death of Dr. John W. Bidwell, 1888, 1897 (Box 11, Folder 387, Reel 6U)
      - Obituary, 1897 (Box 11, Folder 388, Reel 6U)
      - Circular, Undated (Box 11, Folder 389, Reel 6U)
      - Photo of Dr. Bidwell in his carriage (Box 11, Folder 390, Reel 6U)
    - Lawson Bennett Bidwell (1833-1922)
      - Bidwell, Emmeline M. B. (2), 1876-1878 (Box 11, Folder 391, Reel 6U)
      - Bidwell, Marshall Spring, Jr. (7) (Box 11, Folder 392, Reel 6U)
      - Karrick, Ella C. Bidwell (1), 1859 (Box 11, Folder 393, Reel 6U)
      - Karrick, John Walter (1), Circa 1860 (?) (Box 11, Folder 394, Reel 6U)
      - Cards of Mr. and Mrs. Lawson Bennett Bidwell (Box 11, Folder 395, Reel 6U)
      - Obituary, Undated (Box 11, Folder 396, Reel 6U)
      - Photo of Lawson Bennett Bidwell as a young man (Box 11, Folder 397, Reel 6U)
      - Portraits of Lawson Bennett Bidwell (Box 11, Folder 398, Reel 6U)
      - Lawson B. Bidwell family photos (Box 11, Folder 399, Reel 6U)
    - Lawson Brewer Bidwell (1858-1891)
      - Portraits of Lawson Brewer Bidwell as a young man (Box 11, Folder 400, Reel 6U)
    - Lawson Dench Bidwell (1791-1863)
      - Bidwell, John D. (1), 1859 (Box 12, Folder 401, Reel 6U)
      - Bidwell, Lawson Bennett (5), 1856 (Box 12, Folder 402, Reel 6U)
      - Bidwell, Lawson Bennett, letters to his family from construction camps for engineers of the Union Pacific Railroad, Kansas (7), 1863-1864 (Box 12, Folder 403, Reel 6U)
      - Photos of Lawson Dench Bidwell and his wife, Emmeline M. Bidwell (Box 12, Folder 404, Reel 6U)
    - Marshall Spring Bidwell (1824-1902)
      - Photos of Marshall Spring Bidwell (Box 12, Folder 405, Reel 6U)
    - Marshall Spring Bidwell, Jr. (1835-1877)
      - Abbott, Benjamin Vaughan (1), 1861 (Box 12, Folder 406, Reel 6U)
      - Abbott, Jacob (Reverend) (circa 49), 1862-1868 (Box 12, Folder 407, Reel 6U)
      - Abbott, Jacob (Reverend) (circa 27), 1872-1877 (Box 12, Folder 408, Reel 7U)
      - Beecher, Mrs. J. J. (2), 1876-1877 (Box 12, Folder 409, Reel 7U)
      - Beecher, Thomas K. (1), 1877 (Box 12, Folder 410, Reel 7U)
      - Bidwell, Alice C. and Sophia (1), 1854 (Box 12, Folder 411, Reel 7U)
      - Bidwell, Alice C. (circa 35), 1856-1862 (Box 12, Folder 412, Reel 7U)
      - Bidwell, Alice C. (circa 41), 1863 (Box 12, Folder 413, Reel 7U)
      - Bidwell, Alice C. (circa 29), 1864 (Box 12, Folder 414, Reel 7U)
      - Bidwell, Alice C. (circa 32), 1865 (Box 12, Folder 415, Reel 7U)
      - Bidwell, Alice C. (circa 23), 1868-1875 (Box 12, Folder 416, Reel 7U)
      - Bidwell, Clara Emily (11), 1877 (Box 12, Folder 417, Reel 7U)
      - Bidwell, Clara Willcox (6), 1841-1858 (Box 12, Folder 418, Reel 7U)
      - Bidwell, Jacob Abbott (1), 1873 (Box 12, Folder 419, Reel 7U)
      - Bidwell, Lawson Bennett (2), 1863-1864 (Box 12, Folder 420, Reel 7U)
      - Bidwell, Luna S. (1), 1872 (Box 12, Folder 421, Reel 7U)
      - Bidwell, Marshall S. [empty], 1865-1868, 1872 (Box 12, Folder 422, Reel 7U)
        See: box 3, folder 107
      - Bidwell, Mary S. (19), 1867-1877 (Box 12, Folder 423, Reel 7U)
      - Brewer, David J. (Justice) (1), 1866 (Box 12, Folder 424, Reel 7U)
      - Dwight, Professor Theodore W. (2), 1864, 1873 (Box 12, Folder 425, Reel 7U)
      - Foster, L. C. (1), 1877 November 4 (Box 12, Folder 426, Reel 7U)
      - Kip, Leonard W., Jr. (obituary of Reverend Kip included) (29), 1857-1877 (Box 12, Folder 427, Reel 7U)
      - Orton, Thomas Bidwell (8), 1863-1865 (Box 12, Folder 428, Reel 7U)
      - Tomlinson, C. A. (1), 1875 (Box 12, Folder 429, Reel 7U)
      - Townsend, Harriet C. (1), 1877 (Box 12, Folder 430, Reel 7U)
      - Whitney, Mercy Partridge (1), 1864 (Box 12, Folder 431, Reel 7U)
      - Willcox, William M. (2), 1858-1860 (Box 12, Folder 432, Reel 7U)
      - John M. Maison to W. N. Hatch re: death of M. S. Bidwell, Jr. (1), 1877 (Box 12, Folder 433, Reel 7U)
    - Marshall Spring Bidwell, Jr. (Writings)
      - The Mountain Gem, 1861 Oct, 1862 January-April (Box 13, Folder 434, Reel 8U)
      - "My Covenant", 1866 September 30 (Box 13, Folder 435, Reel 8U)
      - "Against the Wind," "I Wish I Was Rich", 1866 (Box 13, Folder 436, Reel 8U)
      - "A Dream" (on mutilating hymns), [1867?] (Box 13, Folder 437, Reel 8U)
      - "Mount Royal No. 1, A Back Town," Riverside Magazine (?), [1867?] (Box 13, Folder 438, Reel 8U)
      - "Mount Royal No. 2, the Paper Mill," Riverside Magazine, 1867 January (Box 13, Folder 439, Reel 8U)
      - "An Iron Mine," Riverside Magazine [empty], 1867 February (Box 13, Folder 440, Reel 8U)
      - "Shoe-pegs", 1867 March (Box 13, Folder 441, Reel 8U)
      - "The Great Snow-storm," Riverside Magazine, No. 2, 1868 (Box 13, Folder 442, Reel 8U)
      - "A Paper-Mill," Riverside Magazine [empty], 1869 October (Box 13, Folder 443, Reel 8U)
      - "What They Did Not Do On the Birthday of Jacob Abbott B., Familiarly Called Snibbuggle-dyboozledom" [empty], 1875 January (Box 13, Folder 444, Reel 8U)
      - Y.M.C.A. spelling match, 3 articles from the Elmira Advertizer and the Elmira Gazette [empty], 1875 April 13 (Box 13, Folder 445, Reel 8U)
      - Drug Store Notes, 1875 June (Box 13, Folder 446, Reel 8U)